What do these three things have in common: a grumpy baby, Harry Potter puppets singing, and a challenge where you pour a bucket of icy water over your head?
这三件事有什么共同点：一个脾气暴躁的婴儿、唱着歌的哈利·波特木偶，以及一个往自己头上倒一桶冰水的挑战？
The answer – they have all 'gone viral'.
答案是——它们都"病毒式传播"了。
The world is becoming more and more digital, and we can't stop it.
世界正变得越来越数字化，我们无法阻止它。
While growing up, instead of wanting to be a doctor or a teacher, some now aspire to be an influencer or content creator, maybe in the hope of suddenly capturing widespread attention.
当逐渐长大，有些人不再想成为医生或老师，而是渴望成为网红或内容创作者，希望也许能突然获得广泛的关注。
It's generally agreed that if your content reaches over 1 million views in a week or less, you have 'gone viral'.
人们普遍认为，如果你的内容在一周或更短时间内达到超过100万的浏览量，你就"病毒式传播"了。
So, how does virality happen?
那么，病毒式传播是如何发生的呢？
The marketing tech company Unruly analysed over 400 billion videos and found that emotional connections, like humour and shock value, resonate the most strongly.
营销科技公司Unruly分析了超过4000亿个视频，发现情感联系，如幽默和震撼价值，最能引起共鸣。
These emotional elements drive us to share that content with others, and the more shares we have, the more seen that content will be.
这些情感元素驱使我们与他人分享内容，分享越多，内容就会被更多人看到。
We should also think about why people want to share content in the first place.
我们还应该思考一下，人们为什么想要分享内容。
Dr Jonah Berger, a Marketing Professor at the Wharton School, says "Sharing allows us to feel connected to others.
沃顿商学院营销学教授约拿·伯杰博士说："分享让我们感觉与他人有联系。
We share emotions, which allow us to deepen the bonds we have with our peers and with our friends".
我们分享情感，这让我们能够加深与同伴和朋友之间的联系。"
So, while we may be behind a screen, we're still online because we want to connect and communicate with others, and going viral is driven by organic sharing, just like word of mouth but in a digital sense.
所以，虽然我们可能身处屏幕之后，但我们仍然在线，因为我们想与他人联系和沟通，而病毒式传播由有机分享驱动，就像口碑传播一样，只不过是数字意义上的。
Though there are other things to consider.
然而还有其他因素需要考虑。
Datadab, a marketing agency, says that our brains are wired to enjoy and recognise patterns, which they say is why internet memes often go viral.
营销机构Datadab表示，我们的大脑天生就喜欢并识别模式，这就是为什么表情包经常病毒式传播。
If we are already familiar with a theme, like a recognisable image on a meme, then it doesn't take long for us to understand the context of a new caption, which our brain enjoys and makes us more likely to share it.
如果我们已经熟悉某个主题，比如表情包上一个可识别的图像，那么我们很快就能理解新标题的背景，我们的大脑喜欢这样，这让我们更有可能分享它。
Timeliness and relevance are also crucial.
时效性和相关性也至关重要。
Content that is relatable, or that aligns with current trends, captures more interest and encourages more sharing.
能引起共鸣或符合当前潮流的内容，能捕获更多吸引力并鼓励更多分享。
So, combine all of these factors and you could have content that goes viral.
所以，结合所有这些因素，你就有可能创作出病毒式传播的内容。